Luke Cooper

11 Waratah Avenue Graceville QLD 4075 0423 083 676 luke.cooper@gmail.com

Objective

I am a software developer with 10+ years of diverse industry experience looking for new programming challenges. I offer experience in C++ and Java technologies on a mixture of client, web and embedded platforms. However I also have a keen interest in learning languages and platforms, and seek to extend my experience into new areas.

Technical Knowledge

Proficient	C++, Java.
Familiar	C, C#, JavaScript, SQL, VB6, Ruby, Python.
Platforms	Windows, Linux, Sony PlayStation 2/3, Nintendo GameCube/Wii, Microsoft Xbox/Xbox 360.
Frameworks/ APIs	Java SE, Java EE, Spring, Hibernate, jQuery, Microsoft .Net, Nintendo RVL SDK, Microsoft X360 XDK, SCEE SDK.

Professional Experience

2011–Present | **Fli**

Flight Centre Software Services Senior Developer

Enhanced and supported a suite of corporate travel booking applications built in a mixture of enterprise Java technologies, which service over 2,500 companies throughout Australasia.

Enhanced security and stability of legacy Java web applications with custom Python scripts to discover SQL injection and cross site scripting vulnerabilities.

Created a Spring/Hibernate Java web application for corporate chartered travel booking. Worked end to end on the application from schema design to jQuery/JSP front end.

2011 **Topcon Positioning Systems** Senior Programmer

Made enhancements in C++ to an MFC-based embedded heavy machinery positioning and control system used by thousands of construction companies worldwide.

2005–2011 | THQ Studio Australia Senior Programmer

Worked as part of a small team that developed a number of console games based on major licenses which sold millions of copies around the world. Credited contributions on five published titles on the Sony PlayStation 2 and 3, Microsoft Xbox and Xbox 360, and the Nintendo GameCube and Wii.

Designed and implemented a wide variety of game systems including cameras, save/load, profiles, user interface, character movement, navigation, front end, sound, editor and a number of complete mini games.

Worked closely with in house clients to ensure that the delivered systems met with the stringent expectations required for publishing a successful title.

Wrote code in C++ using proprietary and off the shelf libraries, with some PC tools implemented using the .NET framework.

2003–2005 | Oracle Corporation Applications Engineer

Made critical repairs in Java and VB6 to a troubled offline sales application. The primary focus of the work was ensuring that the Excel-based application synchronised in a secure and reliable manner with the Oracle Applications database.

Made enhancements and provided technical customer support for a J2EE application that provided a desktop interface using Microsoft Excel to allow for mass data entry into Oracle Applications database tables.

2001–2002 | Electronic Arts Programmer

Implemented a wide variety of art and animation tools within Maya utilising proprietary MEL scripting and C++ plugin DLLs.

Wrote an MP3 decoder in C++ for use on the PC and Sony PlayStation 2.

Education

2012-Present Bachelor of Applied Science QUT Environmental Science Major, Ecology Second Major, current GPA 7.0. 2002 Bachelor of Information Technology (Honours) QUT Graduated with First Class Honours, Awarded University Medal. 1998-2001 Bachelor of Information Technology QUT Software Engineering Major, Graduated with Honours.

Publications

Brown, R., Pham, B., and Cooper, L. (2003). Visual attention-based polygon level of detail management. *GRAPHITE*, pages 55–62

Investigated a novel approach of using the theory of human visual attention to optimise polygon level of detail management in real-time 3D simulations.

Interests

Cycling, the natural world, documentaries, functional programming (Haskell, Common Lisp), learning.

References

Scott Laporte | Team Leader Flight Centre

scott.laporte@gmail.com

 $0421\ 128\ 197$

Dave MacMinn Design Director THQ Studio Australia

david. macminn@playthis studios.com

 $0406\ 522\ 652$